Welcome back to APUSH in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, last video we talked about
World War I in Europe. However, this is
US history, so why don't we now go back
to America and take a look at what it's
like during and after the war. Here's a
good rule to go by. For both World Wars
in American history, America is going to
become kind of unstable. I mean, we
already know lots of America is racist.
I mean, Jim Crow laws still exist and
are still being enforced quite a lot.
But now there are genuine threats in
Europe that America declares as enemies
when they enter the war. And so, during
and after the war, many Americans will
become more willing to limit civil
liberties, especially freedom of speech,
because of anxiety about disloyalty,
radical political ideas, and labor
unrest. Good examples here are the
Espionage and Sedition Acts, which were
acts that criminalized anti-war speech
and the use of quote disloyal language.
You also have the American Protective
League or the APL, who literally
volunteered to report suspicious people.
And after the Russian Revolution started
in 1917, a period in American history
known as the First Red Scare happened,
where there was a big fear that
communists, anarchists, and other
radicals were threatening the United
States. Now, let's transition and talk
about immigration. Because before World
War I, immigration from Europe reached a
very high levels. After the war,
nativism, which was the belief that the
interests of native-born Americans
should be protected against immigrants,
increased. This is where you now see
quotas being implemented, like the
Emergency Quota Act and the 1924
Immigration Act, which would both place
numerical limits on immigration by
creating quotas based on national
origin. A quick note that because of
increased wartime production, there was
a big movement of people from small
towns into big industrial cities for
factory work. Now, this factory work
will mostly be in the north, and a whole
bunch of African Americans still live
down south where they're being forced to
adhere to Jim Crow laws and have
basically no economic opportunities. So,
now when word gets out that the north
has lots of high-paying factory jobs
available, something known as the Great
Migration happens, where a bunch of
African of will move out of the south to
the North. Now, this would create new
black communities, but I do want to
teach something that actually is rarely
taught in American history. That is
something known as the Red Summer of
1919. This is an effect of the Great
Migration, where there will be a lot of
white mobs attacking black communities
in dozens of US cities and towns. On the
screen now are AP style questions for
this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.